Irene Smith

845-699-2258 • irenesmith13@gmail.com http://www.irenesmith.com • @Story Teller

Summary

Hybrid developer/technical writer, with over 30 years' experience with multiple programming languages and technologies. Comfortable with full stack development of both native applications for Windows as well as website and web-based applications. Extensive experience writing API documentation, design and requirement documents, and release notes.

Technical Skills

Application Development: C# and VB.NET, VBA, Python

Web Development: HTML 5, CSS 3, JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, Bootstrap, ASP.NET, ASP 3.0

Database: Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle, Microsoft Access, MongoDB **Graphic**: Adobe PhotoShop, Corel PaintShop Pro, Gimp, Microsoft Visio, Snaglt **Video**: Adobe Premiere Pro, OBS Studio, Adobe After Effects, DaVinci Resolve

Source Control: Git, Perforce, Visual Source Safe (VSS), SVN, Team Foundation Server (TFS)

Development Tools: Sublime Text 3, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, PyCharm

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux (Ubuntu), DOS, macOS

Professional Experience

Google, Inc.

Technical Writer IV (Contract)

8/2023 - 2/2024

Responsibilities

- Write documentation for Google Material Design 3
- Manage current documentation set for Material Design 3.
- Expand content for developer documentation for the Google Material 3/Wiz components.

Amazon Web Services

Code Example Developer (SDE)

9/2020 - 4/2023

Responsibilities

- Develop C# code examples for the AWS SDK for .NET.
- Participated in an initiative to simplify the inclusion of code examples in developer documentation by including specialized comments in the code.
- Developed scenario applications that perform basic tasks for a single AWS service, and crossservice code examples, applications that use multiple AWS services, usually in the form of an ASP .NET application with a React.js front-end.
- Act as on call for the code examples build process which includes creating test builds on a virtual desktop, then initiating the actual build process on the build servers, and then trouble-shooting any problems that arise.

Mozilla

Firefox Developer Content Manager (Contract)

6/2018 - 11/2019

Responsibilities

- Manage content for MDN Web Docs Browser Extensions and Firefox Developer Tools
- Write tutorials for web development.
- Update and refine existing content to reflect new and updated Firefox features and web development best practices.
- Create example code for tutorials and web APIs.

Resume of Irene Smith Page 2

MongoDB

Technical Writer 9/2017 – 3/2018

Responsibilities

- Wrote documentation for MongoDB Atlas
- Collaborated with developers to document new features of MongoDB.
- Created web documentation for MongoDB using restructured Text (reST) and Sphinx.

Moody's Analytics

Technical Writer (Contract)

11/2016 - 6/2017

Responsibilities

- Worked with developers to create technical documentation for Cloud Computing Project
- Created stylesheets and documentation templates.
- Helped define processes for support, development, and technical documentation projects.
- Created quick guides, workflows, and high-level overviews for end users.

Credit Suisse, New York, NY

Technical Writer (Contract)

5/2016 - 9/2016

Responsibilities

- Interviewed Developers to create technical documentation for CCAR Application Modules
- Helped to create SAD (Software Architecture Documentation) document for CCAR Application
- Created data flow and architectural diagrams and application screenshots.
- Wrote reference materials for use by support personnel in application troubleshooting.

BNP Paribas, New York, NY

Developer (Contract)

6/2015 - 12/2015

Responsibilities

- Wrote C# console applications that are run as automated processes to update trade data.
- Created VBA Scripts for Microsoft Excel that create reports for traders.
- Enhanced the UI of a stock pricing application that uses MVC, Angular, and Bootstrap
- Wrote, reviewed, and edited project requirements and user stories.

TIAA-CREF, Charlotte, NC (Remote)

Senior Technical Writer (Contract)

11/2013 - 2/2015

Responsibilities

- Create and maintain templates and VBA macros to simplify document creation.
- Create and update the Developer's Reference for the PRISM API, an application that uses Oracle coherence to cache mainframe data for a Java API
- Create and update a data dictionary for use by PRISM developers.
- Create and update walkthroughs for the PRISM application that include step-by-step instructions and screenshots.

Google, Inc., New York, NY 10011

Technical Writer III (Contract)

7/2012 - 7/2013

Responsibilities

- Wrote technical guides and other documentation using HTML5, CSS3, and markdown.
- Wrote and maintained API documentation for the following Ad Exchange technologies: Buyer REST API, Seller REST API, Buyer SOAP API, Real-time Bidding Protocol
- Wrote the developer's guide for Google's open-source project, Open Bidder

Medidata Solutions, Inc. New York, NY 10003

Senior Programming Technical Communicator Senior Technical Communicator, **Team Lead** 1/2010 - 1/2012

1/2008 – 1/2010

Technical Communicator

9/2006 - 1/2008

Resume of Irene Smith Page 3

Responsibilities

- Scrum Master for internal tools for the Technical Communications department
- Used C# to develop ASP .NET applications, Windows applications, and Microsoft Word add-ins. These tools reduced document preparation time from days to minutes
- Used SQL Server to design and create database model for all internal tools including table design, stored procedures, and functions.
- Lead and mentored, and trained colleagues in creating design specifications and requirements.
- Team Lead for multiple documentation projects.

Times Herald Record, Middletown, NY 10940

Paginator, Assistant Obituary Editor

2/2005 - 1/2006

Responsibilities

- Developed a set of Microsoft Word macros to automate the process preparing obituaries, thus reducing preparation time from over half an hour to less than one minute.
- Documented obituary and classified preparation procedures.
- Prepared obituaries and classified advertising for printing.

Microsoft, Redmond, WA 98052

Programming Writer (FTE), SQL Server Group

4/2000 - 10/2003

Responsibilities

- Developed samples for the **System.Data** namespace of the .NET Framework for versions 1.0, 1.1, and 2.0 using C# and VB .NET to create console and ASP .NET applications.
- Used C++, Visual Basic 6.0, Java (Microsoft J++), JavaScript, and VBScript to develop console application examples for Microsoft ADO, OLE DB, and ODBC API references.
- Developed examples for Microsoft XML using C++ and Visual Basic

mpl2.com, Bellevue, WA

Programming Writer (on contract at Microsoft)

8/1999 - 3/2000

Originally called Meridian Partners, Ltd., mpl2.com placed writers in contract positions at various locations in Redmond, Bellevue, and Seattle including Microsoft.

Responsibilities

- Wrote conceptual and API reference documentation for Microsoft's database objects.
- Used C++, Jscript, Visual Basic 6.0, VBScript, and Java to develop ASP 3.0 and console example applications for Microsoft ADO, OLE DB, and ODBC API references.

Solo Game Development

Designed, coded, created graphics, and wrote context-sensitive help files for several Microsoft Windows commercial game packages:

- Casino Nights (Craps, Roulette, Black Jack, and Video Poker)
- **Dice Games** (Crag, Over 'n Under, and Bird Cage)
- Solitaire (Pyramid and Golf)

Education

University of Phoenix, Online

BS Information Technology/Software Design

Orange County Community College, Middletown, NY

AA, Liberal Arts